so much
[Music]
thank you
alhamdulillah
myself
[Music]
I'm afraid that uh
it will be longer than usual I'll try to
be
very fast so I think of you
attention and concentration
because the
but the first part
we deal with the methodology or
technique in understanding whether
or understanding the Quran or how to get
more out of the Quran
the second good bar would be dedicated
to just one example to illustrate the
pointer scene
the first quarterback
now let me just remind you about the
three quotations from the Quran
you know this very well
the stars have repeated and re-repeated
it
so let me eat it again
first we did not leave anything out of
this scripture
Surah 6 38
remember that now second
shall I seek other than God a source of
law when he revealed to you this book
full detail
of you Lord is complete in true
Injustice Surah 650 14 15. the third one
after saying that he and Allah had put
the Quran together after reciting it he
said then it is we who will explain I
think it's very good
Allah says he has not left anything out
of respect you is complete perfect
heated and he will explain it after he
reveals or after the vegetation
these quotations clearly imply that the
questions raised by the Quran in the
Quran raises question
or questions Race by Muslims
with the answers of this will be found
in the Quran itself
all right if we take these quotations
to us it means if the Quran raises a
question or if we raise a question the
answer must be found in the Quran
to say
now we must not talk in the Quran for
irrelevant or insignificant things
let us not go to Quran to find out a
recipe for chicken curry but
certainly you know the Quran you know
the Quran tell us do not serve poison
Curry to your friends or to your enemies
on the country
if you're cooking Curry and you have a
hungry guess you serve him
feel the hungry
you could run the main instances says
that mean of understanding more
or will come to know the revelations of
Allah
so it seems that there is another way of
knowing the Quran if you understand it
but it is apparent because we will ask
the question who are men of
understanding
they are the Righteous then what did I
choose they are the Believers in their
thoughts who started the Quran
explains it to you directly
and you will know the answer or you have
understanding what you may not
understanding is one to go to Quran so
in any case the answer is indeed Quran I
hope this is a physiological technique
if any gives you big
and not any gives you being since either
a or nothing in any case it is Big so
it's the Quran in any case Federal
directly or use your understanding it's
still to the Quran
yes
there are dangers or obstacles or
Warnings
which I think we should mention in
trying to get explanations to our
questions or to get further elucidation
to quranic verses
the first warning so this is just my
opinion the option to accept it or not
first is too much emphasis
on the Jewish Bible in making us
understand the Quran
I said too much emphasis
the Bible the Jewish Bible in particular
has been edited re-edited and
re-reedited and it has assume its final
form only
150 years before Christ after the
Babylonian captivity
that is after Ezra
838 describes re-edited him
now this is accepted by the biblical
scholarship
and Muslims must not have an inferiority
complex
by defending so much on the Jewish
or
the other way around
Muslims should not be
so proud that they know so much about
the Jewish Bible because you'll find out
if you read the tafsiris of our
ancestors
anything that is difficult in the Quran
to them they call the Bible
not so much to help us understand the
Quran but to show that they know so much
about the Jewish Bible and in trying to
ensure so much that they know about the
Jewish Bible they begin to forget their
own Quran now this happens to Reverend
Muslims
it is a defect which many of us have
including new humble self
in a Catholic School
now we have to be we have to check
ourselves check our pride let me know
something about the Bible and at the
same time not to have this imperiality
complex because in the first hundred
years of Islam when there were
discussions with Christians in Syria and
so on the Muslims have to show that they
also knew what the Christians knew but
this is historia
we must also consider that the Jewish
Bible serves National purposes
genealogical purposes
and that the meaning of the editing it's
always to show that Jews are a distinct
people different from others and these
over emphasis that they are the chosen
people makes them in that editing
emphasize more what is to the direct
interest
also
it's not at all said to always
explain the Quran Through the Bible as
we now have it but
this is a qualification there is nothing
wrong in pointing out certain
correspondences between events or
incidents or characters in the Quran
and those in the Bible this is not just
a matter of scholarship but it is a
matter of developing our understanding
please do not understand me brothers and
sisters of sisters
I was saying we should not consult the
Jewish Bible
I said let us not over a person from the
country it is good to show certain
correspondences if in the final analysis
it will help us understand the Quran
as long as events are consistent well in
good
but when there are discrepancies then
the Quran must be the final one it must
supersede the Bible
other things in the Bible can be
dismissed as irrelevant to the quranic
message
details about ritual details about
sacrifices the lives of their kings
their adulterers their incest all of
these things all irrelevant
the great danger is to interpret or
understand the Quran solely
exclusively in terms of the Bible rather
than letting the Quran explain itself
already Allah explains
himself
he is however does not mean as I said
that we must neglect the Bible in timing
for the country
and I will try to show it will be of
some help in giving additional
information
but as I was trying to show it is an
information that can be reached but by
the Quran it must be totally could be
consistent because this is to say
yeah
and God is not born is Consulting Hadith
to explain the Quran this is
there are people who usually have this
to explain
Quran evident give examples of this
because some of them are very
I mean a very comical I would say this
must be avoided
a criteria to guide us is that the Quran
is Flawless totally consistent as stated
in Surah 18 verse one
speaks of allegories similitus analogies
Etc together with direct pressure
and let me call
Allah he is the one who reveals this
scripture to you with perfect verses
that must be taken literally as
constituting the essence of the
scripture
other persons are allegorical
those who Harbor doubts in their hearts
dwell on the allegorical version
to create confusion and
misrepresentation their own
no one knows the correct interpretation
they're all except God and those who
have founded in knowledge those who
listen to Allah
and uh it's very clear some people avoid
the clear verses of the Quran
allegories
to forget the key verses of the Quran in
order to bring the Ascension and so on
tell us that we should not try to study
this delivery
we should try to understand this
allegories of the Quran but not use them
to create the essential
one of the ideas here of this verse is
that such allegories must not be
interpreted in an arbitrary manner so as
to cause dissension for religious or
sectarian motives their interpretation
must be in terms of the quranic version
in a consistent or logical
manner Allah says
a scripture whose verses were perfectly
designed then elucidated from the one
who is wife was cognition increase Allah
himself
declares that he explains or elucidates
his allegory in the sake of Buddha we
will have one example to explain all of
these things that we have mentioned
along theoretical life
now this is one example for your
elucidation
or an authorization for your edification
and Entertainer foreign
okay
all of us
especially we who live in the western
world
our inheritors or victims of Western
culture requested paintings of western
movies TVs and so on what do we all be
saying we only see Adam and Eve
depicted as physically naked
even before the so-called Paula
there's a movie I saw a movie that is
the trailer
a young boy a young girl running but
there are things around because they're
naked
then you see Michelangelo's painting
happy happy couple
young men a young woman naked
so that is now in our mind
not Paradise what's the kind of a new
discovery
and from this as well as our reading of
the Bible
begin to accept
the second
element is that
because of this nakedness
they use fig leaves okay
I don't know why quickly I have an
answer
a little bit of color so I will not say
but if you look at the shape of the pig
here it's good enough to cover three
aspects of a man's body
okay
the Bible is specifically mentions pink
leaves
huh
the Quran does not say that Adam and Eve
cover themselves with strictly the Quran
only says recovered themselves with
leaves of the garden
more versatile
now the Bible says
that after the fall
when they cover themselves with sweet
dreams
they go towards taught them how to use
skins that's very interesting so Allah
in the Jewish Bible becomes the table
no speaking is not good enough schemes
maybe the garden was becoming call them
okay what does the Quran say okay let's
go slowly
Surah 20 verses 117 118.
17 1180. Allah wants Adam and Eve not to
let Satan lead to their evictment
from the garden
and to cause them visions
four in the garden ain't nothing if
we're guaranteed food and they were
guaranteed that they will not go naked
what follows from this is that Adam and
Eve in the garden were taught not to
worry about food and clothing
things that they will have to worry when
they are evicted
and Allah says and I quote translation
of staff
you are guaranteed that you will not
hunger there in nor go naked conclusion
logical conclusion
is
okay
it's very clear
number two
and Allah says
in Surah 7 27.
oh children of Adam
let not the devil mislead you as he
evicted your parents from Paradise and
remove their garments in order to show
them their bodies this will start
translation others instead of body say
expose the shame the shameful Parts Etc
this is something else I'll just talk
about that that is foreign
now what will Allah said that the devil
will remove your garment if you were
naked
huh
another thing the devil will remove your
garment and you can buy that in the
first
it's very clear they had clothes
Insurance 2017
Allah says
very clear
that Adam and Eve had garments which
Satan removed from them or caused to be
removed from them
now
this is a digression translators and
Julie influence by the Bible put a
parenthesis of the Rope or garment and
they say and Satan took away them from
them
parenthesis of innocent to open coronary
percent of Innocence
the devil took away the Rock
but this little because they read the
Bible and they still think of the Bible
and with the priority competency of
innocent because the idea is that is
innocent
names
in which the Angels did not know so they
have knowledge
more than that
okay
again 22
in Surah 21 21 says
that after they lost their robes or
governments they began to cover
themselves the leaves of the garden
he is from Paradise
in servant 27 26
very beautiful
Allah reveals to them a better garment
or Rainman
you see if you give his Bible
they were naked
they put fig leaves and Allah says his
Skins are better okay
Quran
they were clothed they lost their
clothes
and Adam and Eve made their own clothes
on their own it's very important on
their own
[Music]
garments to cover your bodies for shame
this is translation another
possibilities
to cover your body in explaining it or
magnificent manner there is
luxurious
but I understand what the luxury Visa I
think means explained it or magnificent
and Allah says the Garment of
righteousness is the best
now again translation to the Quran they
say Allah
or Paradise
gave them Splendid garments and then say
however
better than the splendid governments are
the garments of righteousness no this is
wrong
I think it's about translation
when he says the government of
righteousness is prepared because this
is another government huh
actually I think the government of
righteousness is the very government
which Allah gave to Adam something that
is is let me give and partition because
the Arabic word is one and
but again
every translation because they're
influenced by the Jewish Bible they say
Allah
if the Jewish Bible says there are
leaves and then Allah gives them schemes
then Quran Allah gives them his 233
and then say however the garments of
righteousness are better so this is
righteousness explain the Investments of
the garments of righteousness in other
words
he just gave them a garment the Garment
of righteousness which is better but
he's also saying a bit of them the pig
leaves
are garments of righteousness these are
luxury magnificent Or Hispanic so let's
to me this only one row one group is
mentioned in Surah 7 26 regardless of
righteousness is the standard of
luxurious one
and
doesn't say and something else
he could refer to he is good and thought
it's not that he's good now then it
becomes tall it could be both good and
thought but let me know
now let's go to the sequence
Adam and Eve
are wrote
the government
number two they lower the ropes
number three they made their own rope
number four Allah teaches them or
reveals to them the best roads cool
no
the problem of interpretation
is not so good
it is I believe originally wore the
garments of complete
of details
they're already regardless of obedience
in a natural state or as a natural
condition they were just obeying because
that is how they were created that's the
way
verse 21 says
Ada disobeyed Allah
and thus in servant 27. they lost this
rope of a vision yeah if you wear the
law of obedience then you disobey you
lose the rule of this opinion right and
that is what the Quran says took away
from them
their rules because they disobeyed
number three
2021 is
growth themselves
on their own
not very effectively it seems not very
effectively because the last thing this
is not the right one
now he's very important this is now what
man-made huh man-made on his own
and Allah
teaches them
that the garments of righteousness that
is the best and he teaches them how to
to wedding
and this government of righteousness is
not the original government
one of obedience but now being taught by
Allah with the consideration that
mankind has now a free choice to wear it
or not to wedding in other words it must
be acquired by free will the first
government of obedience was just given
to Adam he was not consulted either we
wanted or not he was just kidding but
now regardless of righteousness it's
there
is there
and it's interesting because precisely
in seven
26 God says these are God's Revelations
to you that you may take heed that you
may remember
and that
I stopped with you that the issue
on what nakedness
is or shame is
represents or symbolizes in the story of
Adam here is something else we've not
talk what does nakedness mean around I
did not this is something else
I'm not going to discuss their meaning
all what I'm pointing out here is that
the issue of physical nudity or
physiological nakedness is not the main
issue
is just one instance I'm not saying it's
not involved I'm only saying that it is
only one instance among many other
things that falls under the general
category or issue of obedience and
righteousness
let me repeat again
I am not denying that the element of
decency is involved here
I'm only saying that the element of
efficiency is only one aspect which
falls under the general category of
righteousness all right
and therefore this emphasis about the
nakedness
of Adam and Eve is not so important
to me now
it's not the main issue it is an issue
but not the main issue what is an issue
are really three concepts the concept of
obedience the concept of Disobedience
can be concept of righteousness
and may I ask righteousness taught by
Allah itself
but I understand man makes definitions
like the needs of the government that's
man-made
now when you can't patients let us go
further
remember to be conscious all right
obedience
Disobedience and righteousness
you recall a few weeks ago there was a
discussion in one of our Quran
extensions
section
it has to do with Surah 95
mentioned it is
[Music]
and the olive
and Mom C9